GINA KENNEDY: Hanumanasana is a pose that even some practice yogis are a little bit nervous about trying.
But when you use blocks to come into it, it can make it so much easier.
So, we're going to have Faith demonstrate the split for us.
She's going to come into table top first.
Good.
And I'm just going to have her bring her back knee forward and place her foot on the ground in between her hands.
And we're going to use this block to place right under Faith's hamstring.
And she's very gently and very slowly going to ease her foot forward.
Good.
Now, you could bring this block at whatever level.
We could head it up the other way as well, whatever works for you.
So, you have to experiment just a little. Good. Her toes should be down and back, extending out through her back leg.
Good.
Now, notice how she has to lean forward a little bit.
So, if we bring blocks and place them to the sides, by her hips, she can take her hands to the block and fully lengthen up through her spine.
Good.
Then, she can feel her energy moving from her hips all the way up to the crown of the head, and then, extending out through the ball of her foot and her back big toe.
Just lengthening up.
Good.
And then, as you practice, you can keep lowering your block, maybe using smaller blocks, and then, maybe even a blanket, and lower and lower, until gradually, before you know it, you're in the full split.